PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So far, we've been talking about color
- 到现在 我们已经站在
in terms of wavelength of light and human color receptors.
光的波长以及人类色彩感受器的角度讨论了色彩
That's the physics part of color.
这是色彩的物理角度
Now let's turn to the perceptual part.
现在让我们转向感知的部分
We just learned that every color
我们刚才学到每种颜色都有
has a hue, saturation, and lightness.
色相、饱和度和明度
But colors appear in our world alongside other colors,
但是一种颜色在世界中给人的感觉
and that can really affect how they appear.
会极大的受到它周边颜色的影响
It's also when things can get really, really weird.
这也会让某些事情变得非常非常的奇怪
For example, look at this image.
举个例子 看着这幅图
Notice the two inner color rings.
注意两个的内部颜色环
The one on the left looks green.
左侧那个看起来是绿色的
The one on the right looks blue.
右侧那个看起来是蓝色的
They're different colors, right?
它们时不同颜色 对吧？
No, if you take away the other colors
才不是呢 如果你将其他颜色都去掉
you'll see that they are in fact the same color.
你就会发现它们其实是同一种颜色
And it's not only color which can trick us.
不仅颜色能欺骗我们
Different brightness levels will also affect
不同的明度也会影响
how we perceive an image.
我们看图片的感觉
For example, look at the following greyscale image.
举个例子 看下面的灰度图片
Take a closer looks at these two squares, A and B.
仔细看这两个方块 A 和 B
One is a black square in the light.
一个是在光线下的黑色色块
The other is a light square in shadow.
一个是在暗处的亮色色块
Do you think they are different shades of grey?
你认为它们是不同的灰色么？
Nope, let me show you.
其实不是的 让我展示给你看
They are in fact the same shade of grey.
它们其实是同一种灰色
So clearly not everything is what it seems.
显然不是所有事情都是流于表象的
How we perceive contrast or brightness
我们感受到的对比度或明度
depends very much on the surrounding image.
强烈受到周边图像的影响
And it brings us back to how the brain processes
这让我们回头分析大脑是如何处理
incoming image signals.
输入的图片信号的
The structure of our visual system is optimized
我们视觉系统的构架被优化用于
so that we can do important things,
处理重要的事情
like survive.
比如生存
But a key survival trait is the ability
而生存的一种关键能力就是
to very quickly identify danger.
快速分辨出危险
This requires the ability
这要求
to rapidly refocus our attention when we need to.
当我们需要时 快速集中注意力的能力
Our brain does this by
我们的大脑通过
automatically refocusing our attention
自动集中注意力在
to dramatic changes in color, brightness or movement.
快速变幻的颜色、明度以及运动上
We call this difference in color or illumination contrast.
我们称之为颜色差异或照度对比度
Our brains are hard-wired to notice
我们的大脑对颜色之间的对比
when colors contrast with each other.
的注意力是固化的
In the color mastering suite,
在调色室中
we can adjust the contrast of an entire image
我们可以用对比度滑动条
using a contrast slider.
调整一整幅图像的对比度
It works by increasing or decreasing
它通过增加或减小
the differences in brightness,
画面的明度之间的差距
or the illumination levels across the image.
或照度梯度来起作用
For example, notice the left half of this image
举个例子 我们能发现这幅画面左侧的对比度
has a lower contrast level than the right half.
低于右侧的
Getting this contrast level right
将对比度调整正确
is really important in Pixar movies.
对皮克斯电影来说非常重要
For example, at the end of Inside Out,
举个例子 在《头脑特工队》尾声处
in the headquarters there's a scene
在大脑总部 有一个场景
where the character Anger gets really, really angry
怒怒这个角色非常非常的愤怒
and to sort of heighten this sense of him,
他也一度点亮了这个场景
flames exploding from his head,
火焰从他的大脑上喷射而出之时
the surrounding area of the image is darkened
他周围的环境就被调暗了一些
so that the contrast difference
所以对比度的差异
is really quite extreme in that moment.
对于那个瞬间是至关重要的
These kinds of decisions are made
这类决定都是由
by the Director of Photography.
摄影指导决定的
And casually, we refer to them as the DPs.
一般来说 我们称他们为 PD
Any decision that involves colors
对于任何与颜色或亮度相关的决定
or lighting of any kind will involve the DP.
都会涉及到 PD
Another great example is from the movie Toy Story 3.
另一个绝佳的例子来自于《玩具总动员 3》
Lotso the bear has sort of, in this whole sequence,
熊抱哥在整个片段中
been the only really pink thing in the scene.
是整个场景几乎唯一的粉色物体
It's very much about an emotion of love
这与熊抱哥和主人之间的爱意
between Lotso's owner and the bear.
是紧密联系的
And then as the bear is lost,
然后 当熊抱哥走丢之后
there's a scene at the end where Lotso's looking
在这场结尾处 熊抱哥望向窗内
in the window at his owner and the replacement bear
看到他的主人和新玩具熊时
and then what we're trying to do there
我们尽力做的一件事情是
is sort of have Lotso, the original,
让原来的熊抱哥
seem far less pink than the new bear
比新的玩具熊更加的不粉色
which is pretty much now the sort of center
而新玩具熊则是当下
of attention of love and heightening that perception
爱意注意力的中心 也表现出了
of the difference between how pink
不同程度的粉色
each of them are was very much central to the emotion.
是体现情感走向的关键
In the next exercise,
在下一个练习中
you'll have a chance to play with contrast. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
你将有机会玩一玩对比度 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox